this image was auctioned for 69 million
this video was sold for six million
dollars and there is a plot of land on a
video game
somewhere that was sold for 1.5
million dollars also this 3d house was
sold
for 500 grand and it's not even that
pretty
now the thing that all these things have
in common is the fact that they are
nfts and if you are a developer a gamer
a business owner a collector if you use
the internet at
all you need to understand what nfts are
and how they can and will disrupt your
life and businesses
for example did you know that there is a
casino on a vr
game that is actually hiring full-time
employees
like that means that your job would be
to work full-time inside of a vr
game we are so close to living in a
world like ready player one like the
metaverse is almost
here now if you think that these pieces
of art i just mentioned
are crazy and stupid and who would pay
for that just a scam and a bubble
i'm gonna agree with you we are i think
in bubble territory but before we
dismiss
something as stupid or a scam or just
dumb
let's try to understand it because we
cannot afford to dismiss nfts like
they're stupid
the same way we dismissed bitcoin or
ethereum in 2017.
for example let's take this image right
there this is a 69
million dollar image and this one was
created by the artist called
beeple this image actually consists of 5
other images that people created since
he sat from 2017 and made one
image per day he put them all together
and this is the result you are looking
at
right now and that is what was sold for
69 million dollars yes
maybe the price is insane maybe it's
stupid maybe it's a bubble whatever you
want to call it but the fact that we
live in a world
where an artist can monetize their art
in this way it's amazing
now that is the point of nfts
and there is no into today too many
things to talk about so let's get
started
nft means non-fungible tokens if you
don't know what that means
don't worry we're going to get started
with fungibility first and actually
it sounds harder than what it is
fungibility basically means that one
thing
equals another thing and they are
interchangeable let's say for example i
have a us dollar you have a us dollar
and we exchange those things okay
one equals one that is fungibility now
let's talk about
non-fundability non-vulnerability means
that things are not the same like for
example a plot of land
or a pokemon collectible card or a
limited edition shoes
or a johnson contract like these things
are not the same that
is non-fungible now let's talk about
tokens
what is a token there are some
blockchains like for example ethereum
blockchain that allow you to issue your
own tokens your own
money let's say on top of them for
example the ethereum blockchain has
their own currency and that is ether
right ether right now cost i think a
little bit more than fifteen hundred
dollars
okay but there are tokens on top of the
ethereum blockchain that cost even more
than thirty
thousand dollars like urn finance and
wi-fi that means that you can use the
security of the blockchain to issue your
own tokens and do whatever you want with
them
now if you don't know what blockchain is
or a smart contract make sure you watch
previous videos because i already
explained those concepts now how do you
mean
tokens how do you issue your own tokens
what you can do is just create a smart
contract let's say
and this smart contract will have two
functions one function is it will
receive money
okay and if it receives money it will
send tokens that's it so i can create
let's say
nico coin let's call it nikoi okay so if
i have nikoi i can make a nicoin
contract
and if i get ether or u.s dollars or
whatever it is i will send you
nikon so one ether equals 10 000 nicoins
for example that's how you can issue
your own tokens or one way
of the many there are but what if i made
a contract
that only issues one token
only one not a thousand nico coins one
nico coin and what if
i put an image inside of that token or a
video
or a song or my john's a contract or
whatever it is
this is when boom you have anything
so when you're buying a 69 million
dollar painting you're actually not
buying the painting itself you are
buying a unique
token that will only be issued once and
it's unique
and it has an image inside of it that's
it you're just buying a token
with a file inside of it i know what
you're thinking
it's stupid no i mean why would you buy
an image like anybody can see it so it's
not even private
anybody could download it and resend it
to their friends or print it and put it
on their wall like what is the point of
buying an image who can be so
stupid now i would say that's a very
good argument but also i could make the
same argument with let's say the mona
lisa
why would i let's say go to paris to see
the mona lisa where i can just google
mona lisa and i will have millions of
photos in google
why would i go to paris and do a queue
and pay for everything if i can just
print the mona lisa
and put it on my wall why would i go to
paris then
the answer is i want to go to paris
because i think davinci was
rock star and he did the melissa so i
want to go and see the original thing i
want to go and see
the thing that the vinci made the real
one the original and this is
what nfts do nfts prove originality
nfts prove providence they prove that
something came
from the owner of that thing now here is
when the potential of nfts will become
clear to you and the amount of
disruption
and opportunities that this can create
for many many industries
for example there are projects already
that allow you to tokenize your tweets
into one of these and sell them the
first ever tweet in the twitter website
was done by jack dorsey the creator
of twitter and that tweet was tokenized
made as an nft and it was sold for
almost three
million dollars a couple of days ago
imagine if a music label starts selling
justin bieber's tweets
of what if we could tokenize the
instagram photos from your favorite kpop
artist and you could own
that photo lots of fans will buy those
things and the thing is that because
there are nfds
they can prove that they are the real
thing now this concept is hard to
understand it's hard to really grasp how
big it is
because on the internet we are used to
just copying everything nothing is
original everything is just a copy paste
and nothing has property nothing has
ownership nothing has providence
but with any of these we change this
with any of these we can prove that
something digital
has been owned by some people we can
prove that something digital is created
from a source we can prove all these
things it's the first time that we have
property rights on the internet there is
a video game called axi
infinity in action infinity you can
train breed
raise and educate a little creatures
that you can then
sell this axi right here on screen is
worth
15 million dollars and they have very
good health
speed and skill score also abilities and
parents here in axi infinity is where a
plot of land to train this little cute
thing was sold for
more than one million dollars and people
feel okay buying these things
because with nfts these things are your
property
there is no owner of the game that could
take this away from you
there is no account that somebody will
ban you or move the server
or the company will go bankrupt that is
yours once you have it is yours like i
said this is the first time in the
history on the internet where we can
actually have
online property rights where you can
actually own something digital
we can prove that it's yours and it's
unique as well or take the example of
decentraland the central land is a vr
game that is on the ethereum blockchain
where you can build whatever you want
let's say like minecraft but
it's yours like you can buy land you can
trade your character's clothes
you can do whatever you want and there
is where there is a vr casino hiring
people right now full time literally
somebody will pay you
to go and play with other players that
is 100 possible
right now or imagine tokenizing this
video let's say that now we give the
opportunity to youtube creators to be
able to sell
and trade their videos which video would
you buy which video would you sell
these things are now possible it's
amazing the industries that can benefit
from nfts are so
many but we are also going to have new
industries and new jobs for example
now people need to have any of these
frames like if i buy an nft artwork i
need to display that on my house
so now there is a new market of people
that want to buy nft frames we're gonna
start hanging screens from our walls
that's crazy but it's here
or what if metallica comes to korea and
instead of them selling the tickets
through a third party they just issue
ticket nfts that means that now we're
going to need nft
reader or nft ticket with it like
there's so many new opportunities so
many industries are going to be created
just because of anything as you can see
i could go on forever there are so many
examples of things that could change
but i think you got the point this is a
game changer it's disruptive and i think
we cannot afford to ignore the same way
that we ignore bitcoin or ethereum
because it is crazy or scammy or the
price is too crazy
no way so now you know what nfts are and
why they can be game changers for many
business
across the internet so thank you so much
for watching this video let me know in
the comments what do you think about any
of these do you think they're a scam do
you think there's a bubble do you think
they're stupid and they're gonna go away
i'm always open to opinions and i want
to hear your comments this is the video
four
of a series that i'm trying to make that
explains the crypto bitcoin blockchain
all these crazy concepts in an
easy way i have so many other things to
explain so many concepts
to explore but for this i need your
support i only ask you
three clicks just three clicks like
subscribe
and share that's all i ask you to
continue this series if you think it's
valuable then please
three clicks like subscribe and share
thank you so much for watching the video
don't forget to be happy don't forget
your kimchi that's
amazing see you on the next one bye
you